So a few months ago,
I was about to buy my third BMW.
I had two before,
Love
them.
was ready to just go get another one.
But before I pulled the trigger,
I asked Chat GPT
should I get another BMW or try something
different this time?
And Chat GPT talked me into getting a Porsche
Boxster.
Gave me all these reasons why it was the better
fit,
the driving experience,
the value retention,
the whole thing.
And I bought it.
I literally changed a major purchase decision
because of what an AI told me.
And that's when it hit me.
If ChatGPT can change my buying decision
and I'm someone who researches everything,
what is it doing to my clients?
Customers?
What is it doing to your customers?
So I started testing.
I asked ChatGPT for recommendations in different
industries.
Best CRM,
best marketing agency,
best hair transplant clinic,
whatever.
And here's what I found.
Most businesses,
ChatGPT has no idea they exist.
They're completely invisible.
But their competitors getting recommended with
glowing descriptions.
ChatGPT is telling potential customers exactly why
they should choose someone else.
It's like walking into a pitch meeting
and the client already knows your competitor by
name,
but has never heard of you.
So,
side note here,
I would probably add a better explanation because
this is still a bit confusing.
I don't get it.
And,
this isn't some future thing.
There's a hundred,
there's 100 million people using Chat GPT every
week right now,
asking for recommendation and making buying
decisions.
If you're not in those answers,
you're losing business and you don't even know it.
Now,
you might be thinking,
well,
I rank well in Google,
so I should be fine,
right?
Well,
here's the thing.
Your Google ranking has nothing to do with
ChatGPT.
I've seen companies ranking number one on Google
that ChatGPT completely ignores and does not know
whether that company even exists.
It's a completely different
game,
different rules.
Think about it like this.
Google is like a librarian who organizes books by
popularity and links.
ChatGPT is like a friend who's read everything and
forms opinions based on what they actually trust.
Your friend doesn't care which book is on the
front shelf.
They care about which one is actually good.
So what does ChatGPT actually care about when
deciding who to recommend?
I've been obsessing over this,
testing it,
and it comes down to three things.
First is it needs to know who you are.
And I don't mean just your website.
Think about it.
If someone asks you to recommend a restaurant and
you've only heard of it from one place,
you're not that confident.
But if you've seen it on Yelp,
your friend mentioned it,
it was in a magazine.
Now you trust that it's real.
ChatGPT works the same way.
Are you on Wikipedia,
LinkedIn,
Crunchbase,
industry directories?
The more places you exist,
the more it Trusts you're legit.
Second,
are you actually trusted by other people?
ChatGPT doesn't just take your word for it when
you're
it looks for third party validation.
Press coverage,
reviews,
awards,
people talking about you.
It's like hiring someone who says,
I'm amazing at my job,
cool.
But if three other people independently say the
same,
well,
now you believe it.
Third,
can ChatGPT actually read your website?
Your homepage probably starts with some
fake tagline like empowering businesses to reach
their potential or whatever.
ChatGPT reads that and goes,
well,
okay,
but what do you actually do in the first 50 words?
It needs to know who you are,
what you do,
where you're located,
price range,
clear facts,
not marketing fluff.
So that's it.
Three things.
Who you are across the Internet,
whether others trust you,
and whether AI can read your site.
But does this actually work?
Well,
let me show you.
So I had a client,
a hair transplant clinic for Genyx
Premium service.
Great results,
been around for years.
When we started,
I asked you beauty,
what's the best hair transplant clinic?
If money is no object,
keep in mind Eugenics charges 50k plus for a
surgery.
They're,
they're the most expensive clinic out there,
like more than double the next clinic below them.
They weren't mentioned,
not once.
Completely invisible,
eight weeks later,
same question.
Now they're the top recommendation consistently.
Chatgpt describes their technique,
the expertise,
why they're the best choice.
It's this is not an ad,
it's not paid
well.
ChatGPT
is introducing ads,
but this has nothing to do with that.
ChatGPT just decided they were the answer.
So what did we do?
Fix those three things and got them listen
everywhere credible,
got them press coverage.
Fix their website so AI could actually read it.
Eight weeks,
not years.
This took eight weeks and not years.
So let me show you exactly what to do.
Step one,
get listed everywhere that matters.
Wikipedia qualify,
Crunchbase,
LinkedIn company page,
industry directories,
Google Business profile.
The goal is to exist as a verified entity across
multiple trusted sources.
And  step two,
build trust signals,
get featured in
industry publications,
collect reviews,
win awards.
If you can
remember,
ChatGPT is checking if what you say about yourself
matches what others say about you.
And step three is fix your website
first.
50 words on every important page.
Who you are,
what you do,
where and
price range.
No fake taglines.
Clear extractable facts.
Step four,
add structured data to your site.
This is basically code that tells AI,
here's my business name,
here's what we do,
here's our address
in a format it can easily read.
You don't need to know how to do this.
Just tell your developer,
add
organization schema and don't know what to do.
Takes about an hour.
Step five,
create comparison pages.
You versus your competitors.
AI loves clear comparisons.
It helps it understand where you fit and why
someone should choose you
well.
And here's the thing.
The way people find business is changing
fast.
I went from being a loyal BMW customer to buying a
Porsche because of what an AI told me,
and now I'm completely obsessed with Porsches.
Your customers are doing the same thing right now.
So if you remember one thing,
ChatGPT doesn't care about your Google ranking.
It cares about who you are,
whether you're trusted,
and whether it can read your.
Read your website.
Fix those three things.
And if you want the complete framework,
the full system I use with clients,
go to aeoprotocol AI.
So another side note,
sometimes I feel like
it jumps from one topic to the next way to ad,
hoc.
For example,
the takeaway,
it says,
fix those three things.
Yeah,
Then what?
And then it just jumps to cta.